Andrew Goodenough

Full-Stack Developer

andrewgoodenough9@gmail.com (650) 207-9066 Los Angeles Metropolitan Area GitHub LinkedIn

Summary

I am a Full-Stack Developer proficient in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React.js, and PostgreSQL. My five years as a water polo athlete allowed me to develop my skills in effective communication, teamwork, and keen oversight. I also have a proven background in creating strong relationships with clients and stakeholders.

Skills

Front-End: JavaScript ES6 + JSX || HTML5 & CSS3 || React.js || jQuery Back-End: Node.js || Express || PostgreSQL || Knex.js || Mocha + Chai Other: Github || Vercel || VSCode || Powershell || DBeaver

Recent Projects

Restaurant Reservations App | Project Link | Live Site

- Restaurant Employees are able to use this site to make, edit, cancel reservations as well as seat guests
- All data being hosted through ElephantSQL database, used React.js to make functionality to create and edit reservations
- Tech: JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS

Spotify Clone | Project Link

- Created server and client functionality with React.js
- Plays songs using Spotify's API and displays lyrics
- Tech: JavaScript, React.js, HTML

Flashcard App | Project Link

- Front-end application project built using React.js and Javascript
- Allows a user to flip through decks of flashcards in order to test their knowledge
- Tech: JavaScript, React.js

Experience

ACCOUNT LUXURY MANAGER

Orange County, CA June 2021 – August 2021

The RealReal

- Effectively built rapport by establishing trust and building credibility with clients
- Drove new sales from established consignors
- Leveraged strong consignor relationships to gain referrals for new consignors

FINANCIAL REPRESENTATIVE

Irvine, CA

Northwestern Mutual

January 2021 – June 2021

- Helped clients achieve financial security by providing financial advice and matched solutions with client's needs and goals
- Developed rapport with clients and fostered long-term relationships
- Knowledgeable about Northwestern Mutual financial products and financial market trends
- Built up a sturdy client base, kept client financial plans up-to-date and built a portfolio of new clients on an ongoing basis

Education

CERTIFICATE, THINKFUL

August 2021 - Feb 2022

Thinkful Bootcamp

- Software Engineering, specializing in Web Development
- Developed proficiency in JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3, React.js, and PostgreSQL
- Utilized critical thinking and problem-solving abilities

BACHELOR OF ARTS, COMMUNICATIONS

California State University, Long Beach

NCAA Division I Men's Water Polo Athlete

2016-2021